uoc.edu 2019-09-17

# Privacy policy - Universitat Oberta de Catalunya (UOC)

#### 1\. Data controller

**Identity:** Fundació per a la Universitat Oberta de Catalunya (hereinafter, the “[UOC](http://www.uoc.edu/portal/en/universitat/organitzacio/grup-uoc/index.html)”)  
**Corporate tax code (CIF):** G-60667813  
**Address:** Avinguda del Tibidabo, 39-43, 08035, Barcelona  
**Contact details of data protection officer:** dpd@uoc.edu

The UOC, as the website's controller, in accordance with the provisions of Regulation (EU) 2016/679, of 27 April, on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data (hereinafter, the “GDPR”), and Law 34/2002, of 11 July, on Information Society Services and E-Commerce (LSSICE), informs you that it has implemented the required technical and organizational security measures to guarantee and protect the confidentiality, integrity and availability of personal data entered.

#### 2\. Purpose of the processing

Your personal data will only be used for the following purposes:

  * To manage the sending of information on the UOC's educational offer and to know your opinions on the information we have provided you.  
 
  * To manage the sending of commercial information on other UOC educational offers, as well as academic and institutional information on the acts that are held at the UOC as an institution and on the events and recognitions taking place there. This is done through profiling, both on the part of the UOC and third parties, and the sending of questionnaires related to subjects such as research and innovation.

  * To manage the enrolment of the interested party. Enrolment management means the execution of all administrative procedures necessary for said purpose, such as access, in which the documentation provided by the student is reviewed to ensure the validation that must be carried out by the UOC is correct; attention, in which the channels of communication with the UOC are made available to the student; certification, in which students may request certifications relating to their academic record, and making the Virtual Campus available to the student.  
 
  * To carry out students' registration in G Suite for Education tools and applications, in order to provide adequate academic services, both teaching-related and otherwise, originating from students' requests to access the Virtual Campus and, when the time comes, their enrolment.

We do not process your personal data for any purpose other than the ones described here, except in the case of a legal obligation or a court order.

#### 3\. Duration

Enrolment data are kept throughout the enrolment period. Subsequently, they are blocked until expiry of the applicable mandatory deadline.

Data corresponding to the management of sending information on the UOC's educational offer of the UOC in the chosen educational sphere is kept for the period necessary to carry out this activity.  Subsequently, they are blocked until expiry of the applicable mandatory deadline.

Data provided by the interested party to subscribe to the information service on the UOC's educational offer is kept until the desire to delete them is declared.

#### 4\. Lawful basis for processing

The lawful basis for processing is the consent of the interested party and, if applicable, it may be derived from the provision of an educational service. The lawful basis for processing the personal data related to G Suite for Education resides in the UOC's provision of educational services.

#### 5\. Location where the information is stored

The information provided is stored in the UOC servers or in suppliers or data processing companies that have servers in the territory of the European Union or are protected by the Privacy Shield. 

#### 6\. Transfer

The data provided may be transferred to UOC group companies (UOC X - XTended Studies, S.L.U., Oberta UOC Publishing and UOC Corporate) and data processing companies (such providers of the following services: services for sending notifications, messaging services, agencies, services for generating similar audiences, etc).

International transfers may also occur in accordance with the system of prior authorization and notification established in the current legislation.

#### 7\. Rights of interested parts

You may request to exercise any of the following rights before the UOC by writing to the postal address indicated in the heading or by sending an e-mail to [fuoc_pd@uoc.edu](mailto:fuoc_pd@uoc.edu) and attaching a photocopy of your National ID document or any other equivalent document in law, as stated in the legislation.

If you no longer wish to receive emails from UOC, please click the unsubscribe link included in the footer of every email we send. 

#### 8\. Rights

**Right of access:  **allows the interested party to know and obtain information on the personal data that is subject to processing.

**Right of rectification or deletion:  **allows the correction of errors and the modification of inaccurate and incomplete data.

**Right of cancellation:**  allows the deletion of inadequate or excessive data.

**Right of opposition:**  right of the interested party to prevent the processing of their personal data or to cease the processing being carried out.

**Right to restrict processing:**  involves the marking of stored personal data in order to restrict their future treatment.

**Data portability:**  provision of data of the interested party which is subject to processing so that it may be transferred to another controller without hindrance.

**Right not to be subject to automated individual decisions** for which the interested parties have not given their consent (including profiling).

**Right not to be subject to a decision based on the automated processing** that has legal or similarly significant effects.

**Right to withdraw consent** given at any time.

Interested parties are also entitled to submit a claim to the controlling authority if they consider that their data protection rights have been violated (<http://apdcat.gencat.cat/en/inici/index.html>).

#### 9\. Security

In recognition of the trust placed in us and aware of the importance of protecting and preserving the confidentiality of your personal data, the UOC hereby informs you that it has implemented all necessary technical and organizational measures to ensure their security, as required by the current legislation regulating the security measures for files containing personal data.
